<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DLT-META</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/index.html</link><description>Project Overview DLT-META is a metadata-driven framework designed to work with Databricks Delta Live Tables (DLT). This framework enables the automation of bronze and silver data pipelines by leveraging metadata recorded in an onboarding JSON file. This file, known as the Dataflowspec, serves as the data flow specification, detailing the source and target metadata required for the pipelines.
In practice, a single generic DLT pipeline reads the Dataflowspec and uses it to orchestrate and run the necessary data processing workloads. This approach streamlines the development and management of data pipelines, allowing for a more efficient and scalable data processing workflow</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/getting_started/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/getting_started/index.html</guid><description>The following tutorial will guide you through the process for setting up the DLT-META on your Databricks Lakehouse environment.
You will deploy/configure the solution, configure a database/table for bronze and silver layer as per below stages.</description></item><item><title>Demo</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/demo/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/demo/index.html</guid><description>DAIS 2023 DEMO: Showcases DLT-META’s capabilities of creating Bronze and Silver DLT pipelines with initial and incremental mode automatically. Databricks Techsummit Demo: 100s of data sources ingestion in bronze and silver DLT pipelines automatically. Append FLOW Autoloader Demo: Write to same target from multiple sources using append_flow and adding file metadata using File metadata column Append FLOW Eventhub Demo: Write to same target from multiple sources using append_flow and adding using File metadata column Silver Fanout Demo: This demo will showcase fanout architecture can be implemented in silver layer Apply Changes From Snapshot Demo: This demo will showcase apply_changes_from_snapshot can be implemented inside bronze layer</description></item><item><title>Additional</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/additionals/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/additionals/index.html</guid><description>Integration Tests: To demonstrate DLT-META’s integration tests and CI/CD capabilities using the Databricks SDK, you can follow these steps. These steps involve setting up a testing environment, writing integration tests, and configuring a CI/CD pipeline to run these tests</description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs)</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/faq/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/faq/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contributing</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/contributing/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/contributing/index.html</guid><description>Contributing to DLT-META At present, external contributions are not accepted
Internal Databricks employees are welcome to contribute but are currently limited to tests and supporting refactoring until sufficient tests are in place.</description></item><item><title>Releases</title><link>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/releases/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 14:50:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://databrickslabs.github.io/dlt-meta/releases/index.html</guid><description>v0.0.9 Enhancement Added apply_changes_from_snapshot api support in bronze layer: PR Added dlt append_flow api support for silver layer: PR Added support for file metadata columns for autoloader: PR Added support for Bring your own custom transformation: Issue Added support to Unify PyPI releases with GitHub OIDC: PR Added demo for append_flow and file_metadata options: PR Added Demo for silver fanout architecture: PR Added hugo-theme-relearn themee: PR Added unit tests to showcase silver layer fanout examples: PR Added liquid cluster support: PR Added support for UC Volume + Serverless support for CLI, Integration tests and Demos: PR Added Chaining bronze/silver pipelines into single DLT: PR Updates Fixed issue for No such file or directory: ‘/demo’ :PR Fixed issue DLT-META CLI onboard command issue for Azure: databricks.sdk.errors.platform.ResourceAlreadyExists :PR Fixed issue Changed dbfs.create to mkdirs for CLI: PR Fixed issue DLT-META CLI should use pypi lib instead of whl : PR Fixed issue Onboarding with multiple partition columns errors out: PR v0.0.8 Enhancement Added dlt append_flow api support: PR Added dlt append_flow api support for silver layer: PR Added support for file metadata columns for autoloader: PR Added support for Bring your own custom transformation: Issue Added support to Unify PyPI releases with GitHub OIDC: PR Added demo for append_flow and file_metadata options: PR Added Demo for silver fanout architecture: PR Added documentation in docs site for new features: PR Added unit tests to showcase silver layer fanout examples: PR Updates Fixed issue for No such file or directory: ‘/demo’ :PR Fixed issue DLT-META CLI onboard command issue for Azure: databricks.sdk.errors.platform.ResourceAlreadyExists :PR Fixed issue Changed dbfs.create to mkdirs for CLI: PR Fixed issue DLT-META CLI should use pypi lib instead of whl : PR v0.0.7 Enhancement 1. Mismatched Keys: Update read_dlt_delta() with key “source_database” instead of “database” #33 2. Create dlt-meta cli documentation #45 Readme and docs to include above features v0.0.6 Enhancement 1. Migrate to create_streaming_table api from create_streaming_live_table #37 Updates Readme and docs to include above features Added Data Quality support for silver layer Updated existing demos to incorporate unity catalog and integration test framework integration tests framework which can be used to launch demos v0.0.5 New Features 1. Unity Catalog Support (#28) 2. Databricks Labs CLI Support (#28) Added two commands for DLT-META onboard: Captures all onboarding details from command line and launch onboarding job to your databricks workspace deploy: Captures all DLT pipeline details from command line and launch DLT pipeline to your databricks workspace Updates Readme and docs to include above features Updated existing demos to incorporate unity catalog and integration test framework integration tests framework which can be used to launch demos v0.0.4 Bug Fixes Introduced new source detail option for eventhub: eventhub.accessKeySecretName v0.0.3 Bug Fixes Infer datatypes from sequence_by to __START_AT, __END_AT for apply changes API Removed Git release tag from github actions v0.0.2 New Features Table properties support for bronze, quarantine and silver tables using create_streaming_live_table api call Support for track history column using apply_changes api Support for delta as source Validation for bronze/silver onboarding Bug Fixes Input schema parsing issue in onboarding Updates Readme and docs to include above features v.0.0.1 Release v.0.0.1</description></item></channel></rss>